

Data Center Engineer

Education:

State University of New York College at Buffalo

Bachelor of Science Computer Information Systems 2019 - **GPA 3.94**

Monroe Community College

Associate of Science **Computer Information Systems** 2016

Certification:

Google IT Support Specialization Coursera - Nov 2019



Data Center University Associate Development Path (DCCA) - Mar 2019 Schneider Electric

A+ Computer Repair Certification

Dutchess BOCES - 2013

Awards:

Excellence in Computer Information Systems

SUNY Buffalo State - 2019 This award is given to a few graduating CIS majors who have demonstrated outstanding academic achievement

Exemplary Character and Citizenship

Dwight Bonk (Principal JJHS) 2013

The award recognizes outstanding high school students who do the right thing, are responsible and go out of their way to be kind to others.

Stephen Mogavero

in Stephen-Mogavero 📋 https://smogavero4.github.io/Resume 🦲 GitHub/Smogavero4





Smogavero4@gmail.com



(845) 264-1443

Summary:

Self-motivated with excellent organization and communication skills with a knowledge of both technical and business fundamentals. Equipped with a strong understanding of Windows and Linux OS. Proven leadership and the ability to work with a team. Specialized training skills and the capability to communicate with technical and non-technical individuals. Equipped with 7 years of PC and server hardware and software troubleshooting.

Experience:

BlackRock - Data Center Engineer

- Responsible for supporting and interacting with all IT functions at BlackRock's 50,000 square foot data center.
- Plan and coordinate with other teams to establish downtimes using BlackRock's change management system.
- Racking and patching of servers.

Jan. 2019 to Current

- Execution of the preventative maintenance procedures for all critical infrastructure systems.
- Installing, testing and tracing network cabling infrastructure
- Streamline data center processes to improve efficiency

ColoCrossing - Data Center Operations Coordinator Feb. 2017 to Jan.2019

- Reports to the Director of Information Technology. Directs operations staff throughout the shift.
- Troubleshoot servers that are escalated from other technicians.
- Coordinate technicians to ensure efficiency is met.
- Hold team meetings to set goals for shifts.
- Ensure quality standards are met and work is performed accurately.
- Enter orders into the queue for dedicated and colocated servers.
- Take inventory of hardware and order parts as needed.
- Run MTR, traceroutes in order to diagnose network problems.

Outback Steakhouse – Key Manager

- Responsible for bar inventory and dining room cleanliness.
- Visited guest tables to ensure quality service was provided.
- Made sure guests were welcomed and had an excellent dining experience.
- Resolved guest question or concerns regarding their dining experience.

USS Starcross LLC – IT Manager

- Responsible for 10 technicians
- Troubleshoot Windows and Linux based systems.
- Coordinated a team to ensure work was completed efficiently and timely.

Jul. 2012 to Aug. 2016

Jan. 2016 to Feb. 2017

- Setup and managed the VOIP systems and websites.
- Installed residential and commercial network wiring and wireless systems.
- Built strong relationships with clients and ensured they were satisfied.

Skills:

Management:

- Customer Service
- Scheduling
- Training
- Problem Solving
- Project ManagementBudgeting

Technical:

- HTML/CSS
- Linux OS

Microsoft Office

Troubleshooting

- Virtualization
- Helpdesk
 - Networking

Windows OS

- Technical writing
- Hardware repair